Malik Smith | Software Developer

321-482-2622 | smithmalik2468@gmail.com | Orlando, FL

Summary

An Artificial Intelligence Enthusiasts with strong communication skills and +4 years of programming in software development.

Skills

Python, NLP, LangChain, LLM, Prompt Engineering, Machine Learning, Big Data, GCP, JSON, R, scikit-learn, Front-End Development, API, C++

Project Experience

LangChain Platform Developer | Resume Chat Bot | 10/19/2023

- Developed Project files Architecture for seamless continuous integration and chose a reputable cloud hosting software for collaboration and source controls.
- Managed environment variables and gitignore configurations.
- Installed and documented project packages and libraries.
- Used Python to Load and Split documents into a vector store with OpenAl embeddings for semantic search.
- Created a similarity search functionality in conjunction with a Conversational Retrieval Chain to add context to the model during the retrieval phase.
- Created GUI to display Chats and chat history.
- Created component to upload proprietary data to the application so that you can ask open-ended questions about your own data.

Python Developer | PackGenius- Smart Packing Assistant with OpenAl and Speech Recognition | October 2022

- Developed Project files Architecture for seamless continuous integration and chose a reputable cloud hosting software for collaboration and source controls.
- Used Python to Integrate a weather API to retrieve and display weather information to user.
- Used Python to Integrate OpenAI API for list generations through functions and classes.
- Integrated multiple prompts for different scenarios.
- Integrated voice recognition speech to text and text to speech using python libraries.
- Added functionality to remove and delete generated items from list view.

Data Analysis (Machine Learning Developer) | District Median Housing Price Predictor | Febuary 2023

- Used Python packages to perform exploratory data Analysis on heterogeneous data as needed.
- Used Python Packages to Create Visualizations and plots based on variables such as location, size, and prices.
- Used Python packages to perform data manipulation and feature engineering to improve accuracy of model.
- Used Python packaged to validate accuracy of model with methods of splitting test and validation data.
- Used a Regression Model, Decision Tree, and SVM and compare results to find most effective model.
- Predicted, scored, and fine-tuned model for results.
- Hosted project on cloud for easy accessibility.

C++ Developer | Client-Server Chat Application | June 2022

- Designed Architecture for project flow.
- Created one Server application and one Client Application in C++.
- Established Connection from client to server via TCP and UDP broadcast implementation utilizing winsock library.
- Created functions to parse data, register users, send and receive messages, track connected users, get list of connected users and log and/or display chat messages.
- Allowed server to accept multiple clients to connect.

Experience

Solution Analyst | 08/2023 - Present | Deloitte Consulting LLP | Orlando, FL

- Responsible for creating the logic and flow which automated 35 user work processes that lead to a 10% increase rate in user productivity and 2 timely, and successful deployment releases into production of a full scale application.
- Added to knowledge base with current documentations ultimately contributing 20+ detailed resolution, and troubleshooting steps for current work processes.
- Supported testing and debugging efforts which lead to catching 2 bugs before being released to production.

Dell Technologies Desktop Support Agent | 05/2020 - 10/2020 | Alorica | Lake Mary , FL

Aviation Ordnance Technician | 06/2015 - 06/2020 | United States Navy, USN | Lemoore, California

Certificates

Google Data Analytics Specialization | 07/19/2023

Education

B.S. Computer Science | Full Sail University | 03/2023 | Winter, FL 3.13 GPA

Links

Github: https://github.com/Creating-Code-CC

LinkedIn: www.linkedin.com/in/malik-smith-creating-code

references available upon requests.